# Tim Carlock

# Web Developer and Usability Enthusiast

300 3rd St, Apt 605 San Francisco, CA 94107 314.719.9051

timothy.carlock@gmail.com http://timcarlock.com



#### Overview

I have over ten years of software strategy, design and development experience, and I'm extremely passionate about product design and user experience. I've worked as an engineer and product lead with experience in financial services, consumer tech and business software. I also founded a software startup where I was responsible for product strategy and design.

# **Experience**

#### Web Engineer // Learnist // San Francisco, CA

Feb 2013 - Present

I work on the web team as a full-stack engineer where I'm responsible for the design, development and deployment of new features. I work primarily with Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, and other related technologies and tools such as CSS3, Sass, CoffeeScript, New Relic, Redis and Rspec.

- Rebuilt the email-preferences system including a redesign of the data-storage architecture, server-side permission checking and the UI for preference management.
- Redesigned and refactored key application components including tag clouds, link curation, comments and user/board statistics.
- Redesigned the UI and workflow for the content-curation process and created proposed UI redesigns of the two primary site pages.
- Helped implement a new content-subscription experience whereby users are provided a daily email for content and their progress through content is tracked.

#### Software Engineer // Expedia // San Francisco, CA

May 2012 - Feb 2013

I worked on the social team where I was responsible for Facebook integration and developing a reviews API using Java, Spring and MongoDB.

- Developed an API to serve localized hotel reviews for multiple sites including hotel search, hotel details and travel packages. The API was developed using Java/Spring, MongoDB, EC2 and Yammer Metrics.
- Helped manage deployment and provisioning using Jenkins, Capistrano and Chef.
- Participated in daily standups, as well as bi-weekly sprint planning and retrospectives.

#### Co-Founder & Product Lead // Nexly // San Francisco, CA

August 2009 - April 2012

Nexly was a toolset that helped business-service providers use client feedback to generate and track leads. I was responsible for product strategy, design and development.

- Developed the application using Rails and PostgreSQL running on Heroku. Other technologies included CSS3, jQuery, CoffeeScript, Sass and HAML.
- Integrated with various APIs including Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn.
- Worked closely with users to understand key problems and needs, identify features and develop a product roadmap.

 Hired and managed contract designers and developers and oversaw all aspects of feature development, deployment and review.

## IT Manager - Software Products // Hammond Associates // St. Louis, MO

May 2004 - August 2009

I built and managed a product-development group that was responsible for developing portfolio-management and data-analysis applications for both internal and external use.

- Managed the company's overarching software strategy and supervised up to six direct reports including user-support analysts, a project manager and application developers.
- Worked with department directors to identify new projects, develop project roadmaps, and present project proposals to senior management.
- Oversaw the design and development various applications including data warehousing, portfolio-analysis and management and client reporting.

## **Education**

#### University of Missouri - St Louis // Bachelor of Science - IS

August 2004

• 3.91 Cumulative G.P.A.

#### University of Missouri - St Louis // Bachelor of Science - Finance

August 2004

- Student of the Pierre Laclede Honors College.
- President of the Delta Sigma Pi Business Fraternity.

## **Skills**

Operating Systems: OS X , Linux (Ubuntu), Windows

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript/CoffeeScript, HTML/HAML, CSS/Sass, Java, C#, SQL

Data Stores: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, SQL Server

Frameworks/Libraries: Rails, jQuery, AngularJS, BackboneJS, Bootstrap

Gems: rspec, devise, cancan, FactoryGirl, paperclip, thinking-sphinx, omniauth, sunspot, koala, rabl, jbuilder

Dev/Design Tools: Pivotal Tracker, RVM, Git, Github, Jenkins, TextMate, Sublime Text, Illustrator, Photoshop, easel.io, Balsamiq